Guide to the Wallace Notestein Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1899-1969; Series I; (11 boxes)
  - Thirsk, Joan, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 725)
  - Thomas, Gladys Scott, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 726)
  - Thomas, Roger, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 727)
  - Thompson, Faith, undated (Box 8, Folder 728)
  - Thompson, J. G., 1902 (Box 8, Folder 729)
  - Thomson, Alexander, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 730)
  - Thomson, George, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 731)
  - Thomson, Mark A., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 732)
  - Thorne, Samuel E., 1949 (Box 8, Folder 733)
  - Thorp, Thomas, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 734)
  - Thurston, Florence, undated (Box 8, Folder 735)
  - Thurston, Mary Wharton, 1913-1914, undated (Box 8, Folder 736)
  - Tillyard, E. M. W., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 737)
  - Timings, E. K., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 738)
  - Tinker, C. B., 1931-1944, undated (Box 8, Folder 739)
  - Toensmeier, Carl M., undated (Box 8, Folder 740)
  - Tomlinson, H., 1930 (Box 8, Folder 741)
  - Tout, Mary, 1929-1948 (Box 8, Folder 742)
  - Townsend, Mrs. Frederick, undated (Box 8, Folder 743)
  - Toynbee, Arnold and Rosalind, 1935-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 744)
  - Treman, Robert H., 1928 (Box 8, Folder 745)
  - Trevelyan, G. M., 1931 (Box 8, Folder 746)
  - Trevor-Roper, G. R., 1951-1968 (Box 8, Folder 747)
  - Trollope, E. M., 1912 (Box 8, Folder 748)
  - Trumbo, Eunice, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 749)
  - Tweedsmuir, Lord and Susan, 1939-1955 (Box 8, Folder 750)
  - Tucker, Gilbert, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 751)
  - Turner, Edward Raymond, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 752)
  - Turner, Ralph E., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 753)
  - Tuttee, Emmerson, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 754)
  - Udal, N. Robin, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 755)
  - Upton, Eleanor, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 756)
  - Valentine, Alan, 1931-1941 (Box 8, Folder 757)
  - Valentine, Lucia, undated (Box 8, Folder 758)
  - Van Aken, C. R., 1902, undated (Box 8, Folder 759)
  - Van Doren, Harold, undated (Box 8, Folder 760)
  - Van Doren, Irita, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 761)
  - Van Erde, K., 1948 (Box 8, Folder 762)
  - Van Tyne, Claude H., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 763)
  - Vance, Anne H., 1927, undated (Box 8, Folder 764)
  - Vance, William R., 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 765)
  - Veale, Douglas, 1948, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 766)
  - Verney, Harry C. W., 1945 (Box 8, Folder 767)
  - Verney, Ralph B., 1939 (Box 8, Folder 768)
  - Verney, Ruth, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 768)
  - de Villiers, Anne and E., 1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 769)
  - Vincent, George E. and Louise, 1912-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 770)
  - Vincent, John H., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 771)
  - Wake, Joan, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 772)
  - Waldman, Milton, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 773)
  - Walker, Curtis H., 1905-1945 (Box 8, Folder 774)
  - Wallace, B. B., undated (Box 8, Folder 775)
  - Wallace, De Witt, 1932-1967 (Box 8, Folder 776)
  - Wallace, Elizabeth, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 777)
  - Wallace, James, 1907-1937 (Box 8, Folder 778)
  - Wallace, M. Janet, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 779)
  - Walls, H. J., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 780)
  - Ward, W. D., 1901 (Box 8, Folder 781)
  - Watrous, Alice T., 1947, undated (Box 8, Folder 782)
  - Wayne, Anthony, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 783)
  - Webber, William Sloan, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 784)
  - Webster, Charles V., 1949 (Box 8, Folder 785)
  - Wedgwood, Josiah C., 1929-1935 (Box 8, Folder 786)
  - Wedgwood, Veronica, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 787)
  - Welles, C. Bradford, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 788)
  - Wells, Helen, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 789)
  - Wells, Herman M., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 790)
  - West, W. M., 1908 (Box 9, Folder 791)
  - Westergaard, W., 1945 (Box 9, Folder 792)
  - Westermann, Will L., 1908-1939 (Box 9, Folder 793)
  - Wharton, A. E., 1934 (Box 9, Folder 794)
  - Wheeler, Stanley, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 795)
  - White, Albert Beebe, 1908-1947, undated (Box 9, Folder 796)
  - Whiteman, Anne, 1951-1965 (Box 9, Folder 797)
  - Whitney, Josepha, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 798)
  - Whitridge, Arnold and Doris, 1937-1943 (Box 9, Folder 799)
  - Wild, J. H. S., 1949 (Box 9, Folder 800)
  - Wilder, Isabel, undated (Box 9, Folder 801)
  - Wilhelm, Charlot, undated (Box 9, Folder 802)
  - Wilkinson, B., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 803)
  - Wilkinson, Spencer, 1931-1932 (Box 9, Folder 804)
  - Willard, James F., 1928-1934 (Box 9, Folder 805)
  - Willcox, Walter F., 1951-1955 (Box 9, Folder 806)
  - Willcox, William and Alice, 1927-1965, undated (Box 9, Folder 807)
  - Williams, Basil, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 808)
  - Williams, C. M., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 809)
  - Williams, J. W., 1946 (Box 9, Folder 810)
  - Williams, W. R., 1934 (Box 9, Folder 811)
  - Williams Wayland W., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 812)
  - Williamson, F. E., 1935 (Box 9, Folder 813)
  - Willis, Olin M., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 814)
  - Winkle, Wendell L., 1940-1944 (Box 9, Folder 815)
  - Willson, David and Molly, 1928-1949 (Box 9, Folder 816)
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1947, undated (Box 9, Folder 817)
  - Wilson, Hester, undated (Box 9, Folder 818)
  - Wishart, Charles F., 1935 (Box 9, Folder 819)
  - Woodbine, George E. and Helen, 1906-1927, undated (Box 9, Folder 820)
  - Woodrow, Caroline I., 1913 (Box 9, Folder 821)
  - Woods, John A., undated (Box 9, Folder 822)
  - Woodward, Ernest L., 1939-1968 (Box 9, Folder 823)
  - Woodward, Ernest L., undated (Box 9, Folder 824)
  - Woodworth, W. Scott, undated (Box 9, Folder 825)
  - Worcester, D. K., Jr., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 826)
  - Wright, B. F. and M. C., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 827)
  - Young, Charles, undated (Box 9, Folder 828)
  - Young, Eleanor Winthrop, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 829)
  - Young, G. M., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 830)
  - Young, Tom, undated (Box 9, Folder 831)
  - Zeleny, John, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 832)
  - Unidentified, 1900-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 833-842)
- Manuscripts, 1906, 1921-1958, undated; Series II; 4
  Series II contains Manuscript materials arranged by type i.e., diary, notes taken in research for lectures, speeches, and miscellaneous writings (probably unpublished). The writings include an undated Valedictory Address and articles entitled: "A Lonely Grave," "The Education of Prof. Eddy," "An Impressive Picture," "The End of an English Era," "To England's Account," and "the Speaker of the House of Commons."
  - Diary [Dec. 1906] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Writings, 1921-1958 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Germany (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Future of German Austria, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - German Economic Losses, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Old, New Germany (Translation Bureau), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - A Statistical analysis of Germany's Loss by the Cession of the West Bank of the Rhine, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "The Passing of County in England", undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Printed material, 1912-1957, undated; Series III; 2
  Series III contains Printed Matter arranged by type - miscellaneous and newspaper clippings - covering the period from 1912-1957.
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1912-1950, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925-1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Subject file, 1900-1968, undated; Series IV; 8
  Series IV contains 8 folders arranged by type and covers the period from 1900 to 1968. Topics included are: Awards, Invitations, Reviews, Reunion, Coolege of Wooster, 1902-1910, Memorandums, and materials pertaining to the History Department, Yale University, Yale University Press, and the Parliamentary Diaries Project, 1962-1968.
  - Awards, 1907-1967 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - History Department, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1900-1948, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Memorandums, 1946-1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Parliamentary Diaries Project, 1962-1968, n. d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Reunion, College of Wooster, 1902-1910 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1926-1944 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Yale University Press, 1939-1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Letters of sympathy, 1969; Series V; (1 box)
  Series V contains 18 folders of letters of sympathy received by Mrs. Wallace Notestein on the death of her husband arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Included in these folders are occassional letters of acknowledgement by Mrs. Notestein, which appear directly after the specific letter acknowledged. Series V also contains three folders of materials pertaining to scknowledgements, telegrams received, and funeral arrangements.
  - Letters of sympathy, 1969
    - A (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ba - Be (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bl - Bz (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ca - Col (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Con - Cz (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - D (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - E - F (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - G (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ha (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - He - Hz (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - I - K (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - L (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - M (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - N - Q (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - R (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - S (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - T - V (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - W - Z (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Flower cards and telegrams (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Mrs. Notestein's guide to card file (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Funeral arrangements (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Ada Comstock Notestein, 1945-1949; Series VI; 1/2 archive box
  Series VI contains 3 folders arranged by topic which include correspondence and subject files of Ada Comstock Notestein regarding Yale.
  - Committee on the Status and Needs of Women Students at Yale, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Yale Council's Committee on the Humanities, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)